Muhammad Fathir Irhas

Jakarta - Tangerang

🛘 (+62) 812-2444-1284 | 🗷 fathir.irhas@outlook.com | 🏕 https://mfathirirhas.github.io | 🗖 mfathirirhas | 🗖 mfathirirhas

Summary _

Highly passionate and enthusiast Software Engineer mostly in backend development and little frontend stuffs. Always learning to improve skills and willing to share. Able to work independently and in team. Write good and testable code and refactor them if needed. Have experiences writing web services using REST APIs to be consumed by web and mobile.

Education

Telkom University Bandung, Indonesia

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE(S.KOM)

2012 - 2016

• GPA: 3.34

Experience

Anabatic Technologies

Serpong Tangerang, Indonesia

Jan 2018 - Present

TECHNICAL CONSULTANT

- Provide and deliver solutions to the clients
- · Monitor client's app running
- Support product development and customization

Emporia Digital Raya, Anabatic Tech.

Serpong Tangerang, Indonesia

Nov 2016 - Dec 2017

- · Work in Agile running sprint every 2 weeks.
- · Maintain Main site.

PRACTICUM ASSISTANT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Develop UI components using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and JSP.
- · Develop web services in form of REST APIs, firebase push notif, mail services, authentication for mobile apps using PHP, Java and MySQL.
- · Versioning and deployment.

Chevron Pacific Indonesia Duri Riau, Indonesia

• Create simple web app using C# ASP.Net to handle request for well surveys.

• Internship under UTC-POD Team in IT Departement.

Informatics Lab, Telkom University

Bandung, Indonesia

2013 - 2015

2015

- · Held and leaded the Practicum Class.
- Helped organize and control the practicum.
- Taught and mentor students.
- Helped students in debugging the problems they found in their code.
- Evaluate works and results of every students at the end of practicum.

Skill

INTERNSHIP

- · Languages: Go, PHP, C#, HTML/CSS, Javascript.
- MySQL, ASP.Net, Postman, Apache Tomcat, Linux.
- · Web services, REST APIs, Auths, SQL, Unit testing.

• Nodejs/expressjs, Java, Python, Laravel, Wordpress, Jekyll.

Project_

Well Surveys Management

Chevron Pacific Indonesia, Duri,

Riau

2015

WEB APP TO HANDLE REQUEST FOR WELL SURVEYS. INTERNSHIP PROJECT.

Created Auth and CRUD services to manage requests

Color Image Blind Watermarking using Discrete Wavelet Transform and Hidden Markov

Telkom University, Bandung, Indonesia

COLLEGE FINAL PROJECT 2015 - 2016

- · Dekstop app created using C#
- · Implement blind watermarking using black and white image as information embedded into host image.
- Using Discrete Wavelet Transform for mapping embed scheme.
- Using Hidden Markov Model to detect clean or attacked watermark in host image.

Eksporaja.com

Emporia Digital, Serpong, Indonesia

A PROJECT WHILE WORKING IN EMPORIA. WEB APP TO SUBSCRIBE TO ALIBABA GGS

Nov 2016 - Mar 2017

- · Web app created using Java, MySQL, Hibernate, and Tomcat for backend. HTML/CSS, Javascript, JSP for frontend
- Provide subscription to Alibaba GGS for SMEs in Indonesia.
- Provide payment gateway for Alibaba GGS Subscription using Doku.

Infodaily

Emporia Digital, Serpong, Indonesia

A PROJECT WHILE WORKING IN EMPORIA. B2C MOBILE APP

Mar 2017 - February 2018

- A mobile app to provide B2C services(food, mart, billing payment) and places directory.
- · Web services in form of REST APIs, Push notif, mail services, payment gateway, and authentication using PHP and AJAX .
- · Back office created using wordpress.
- · Mobile app created using Android and iOS

Activity

SMAN 1 Bukittinggi Forum Studi Islam

Bukittinggi, Indonesia

HIGH SCHOOL ROHIS COMMUNITY

2009 - 2012

Informatics Lab, Telkom University

informatics Lab, fetkom University

Bandung, Indonesia 2013 - 2015

PRACTICUM ASSISTANT

· Held and support main practicum

· Held religious activities in school

Bandung, Indonesia

USBM, Telkom University
Unit Seni Budaya Minangkabau

2012 - 2014

· Student community related to Minangkabau culture

Software Engineering Lab, Telkom University

Bandung, Indonesia

LAB ASSISTANT

2015 - 2016

Oct 2015

Study and research group. Held and support some lab activities including tutoring, mentoring, sharing knowledge, workshop, movies, game, game development community indie game developer enthusiast and other activities.

Hackathon MDK 2.0 Bandung, Indonesia

CONTESTANT

- Participate in second Hackathon held by Telkom around Indonesia.
- Developed simple web services to be consumed by Android

Microsoft Student Partner

Bandung, Indonesia

Мемвеr 2015 - 2016

 Participated in student community for Microsoft related technologies. Sharing things related to Microsoft technologies to nearest friend and community.

Other.

Blog: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/blog **More**: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/resume **Portfolio**: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/portfolio